## Ghulaam Ellahi

Email: gm.ellahi@gmail.com

## **Personal Profile**

I am a full-time wheelchair user and a recent graduate in Computer Games Technology with a passion and keen interest for Programming. Having good problem-solving skills, my strengths lie in Games Programming however, I also have experience in Web-Development and can adapt myself to quickly learn various other programming languages. Furthermore, I have great communication and teamworking skills which help me collaborate effectively and work efficiently with a variety of audiences and also autonomously. I enjoy attending online seminars and also participate in game-jams and hackathons.

## **Education**

#### Birmingham City University [2015 - 2018]

• BSc (Hons) Computer Games Technology - 2:1

#### Joseph Chamberlain Sixth Form College [2013 - 2015]

BTEC Level 3 ICT (National Extended Diploma) - D\*D\*D\*

#### Hall Green Secondary School [2008 - 2013]

• 10 GCSE's - Grades A - C including English (B) and Maths (C)

## **Employment and Work Experience**

#### Virtual Tutor [Nov 2020 - Present]

Currently I am a virtual tutor at FunTech and educate students from ages 10 - 14 on procedural programming using Python. At the end of the virtual course that I teach, students are more comfortable with a range of Python concepts, understand what they do and also can develop their own programs using an IDE (Integrated Development Environment). The IDE that I teach the students to use is Pycharm, which is purely used for developing programs using Python. Furthermore, I also educate students on the Scratch visual programming language course that FunTech provides.

#### Student Ambassador [Oct 2017 - June 2018]

I worked as a Student Ambassador on open-days and applicant visit days at Birmingham City University, in order to assist prospective students by providing more in-depth information about the course I studied, so that they can decide whether or not the course is right for them.

#### Marketing Assistant [June 2012 - July 2012]

I conducted work experience with an ICT marketing firm called 'Tomorrow People'. This helped me gain vital ICT and marketing skills. In addition, I have learned about the inbound marketing and content marketing processes as well as how the processes affect 'Tomorrow People' as an overall business.

## Final Year Project

For my final year project, I developed an Augmented Reality application which helped to educate people about the planets in our solar system. The underlying aim was to investigate whether Augmented Reality supported a range of different learning styles. Furthermore, I also collaborated with the Birmingham Science Museum (Thinktank) and designed and implanted an exhibition which was held at the planetarium in the museum, in order to promote the museum whilst also gaining extra feedback on my Augmented Reality application for my dissertation.

# **Technical Skills**

•	Games Development - Unity, Visual Studio, Irrlicht and DirectX	****
•	General Programming - C#, C++ and Python etc.	****
•	Web Development - HTML and CSS	***
•	Modern Technologies - VR, AR and MR	****
•	Application Development - XCode and Android Studio	***

## **Achievements**

#### Joseph Chamberlain Sixth Form College - Certificate of Commendation

• I achieved an award from my college in recognition of my achievement.

#### **Second Team Player of the Year**

• I received an award for being the player of the year in the second team, when I used to play for the Aston Villa Rockets wheelchair football team. In addition, I also received various other medals whilst playing for the football team.

### **Contact**

• Email: gm.ellahi@gmail.com

• Website (Portfolio): ghully007.github.io

• LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ghulaam-ellahi-307a0613a/

## **References**

References available upon request.